I'll take care of No. 8.
8號就由我…
What should I do?
該怎麼辦？
I can't use this attack on Vice-Captain Hoshina!
我不能把這種拳頭揮向保科副隊長
The blade went through.
砍傷你了
He's not someone I can fight off while holding back.
不行，手下留情打不過他的
He's too fast. I can't heal myself quickly enough!
攻擊速度太快了，根本來不及硬質化
He's much faster than the humanoid kaiju from before!
只論動作 他比剛剛的人型怪獸快多了
When I saw Kikoru's moves for the first time,
第一次看到琪歌露的動作時
it was unbelievable to me.
就覺得很不得了
But he's in a completely different world from hers.
但他又是不同的境界
These aren't the movements of a human!
這已經不是人類能做到的動作了！
I dodged that move! What is this?
我明明躲開了，這是什麼？
An imperceptible sword attack?
看不見的斬擊？
Core, confirmed.
確認核心位置
Looks like I'm also not human, huh?
我終於也不算是人類了啊
Now that I've tried it,
試過之後才知道
I know reconstruction takes up a lot of stamina.
復原需要消耗大量體力
I can't keep taking these attacks!
再多挨幾刀可不妙
Hey, seriously? I'm giving him the best I've got.
喂，真的假的？ 我可是相當認真進攻呢
This guy is probably…
這傢伙恐怕…
well over Fortitude 8.0.
是怪獸規模8.0以上
He'd be classified as a Daikaiju.
大怪獸級別的個體
But what is this strangeness I've been feeling?
但是為什麼？一直覺得哪裡不太對勁
That's not my problem.
算了
A double-combo attack of the invisible blade!
看不見刀刃的二連擊！
That's not it. The double-combo was just a decoy.
不對，二連擊只是幌子
Mist Slasher!
幻霞襲！
A triple-combo attack?
是三連擊！
I got him.
討伐完成
The blade… The blade won't move.
刀刃…卡住了
That was close. He was more powerful than I thought.
好險，威力比想像中還強
But now that he's seen my core,
但既然被看見核心位置
I knew that would be his target!
我就知道一定會瞄準這裡
Shit!
不好！
I let him get away.
讓他跑了
Reporting back.
報告
Kaiju No. 8
怪獸8號
has escaped.
逃亡
Kaiju No. 8. Kafka Hibino…
怪獸8號，日比野卡夫卡
I'll take it from here.
接下來就交給我吧
Can I continue to believe in him?
我繼續這樣相信那傢伙好嗎？
I'm back.
我回來了
Sorry for making you worry.
抱歉，讓你擔心了
What? I wasn't worried at all.
什麼？我才沒有擔心呢！
I have more important things to say to you right now.
不說這個了，我有很多話要跟你…
Hey!
喂！
Sorry.
抱歉
I let him get away.
讓他逃走了
The one that hurt you.
打傷你的那傢伙
I don't care about that.
我是沒關係啦
I'll kill him myself.
我自已會殺掉他
Where are you going in that state?
等一下，你拖著這身體要去哪裡？
Ichikawa and Iharu are really hurt.
市川和伊春傷得很重
I have to go to them.
我得去救他們
Like you're going to be of any help.
你去了又能做什麼？
I'm sure they're fine.
一定沒事的
The Defense Force is already incorporating
防衛隊已經開始把怪獸的復原能力
kaiju reconstruction into their own technology.
運用到醫療技術上了
Worry about yourself right now, Kafka!
比起他們，還是先擔心你自己吧！
Officers found you, and you interacted with Vice-Captain Hoshina!
不只被隊員發現 還和保科副隊長接觸了！
They may have figured something out at this point!
要是因此被發現蛛絲馬跡也不奇怪！
You look depressed. That's new.
難得看你這麼沮喪
Damn. You found me at my lowest state.
嗚哇，被你看到超遜的一面了
-I'll keep a record of it to commemorate. -Stop it!
-我來拍張紀念照吧 -快住手
So, was he strong, this Kaiju No. 8?
所以，怪獸8號很強嗎？
He's probably a Daikaiju.
他可能是“大怪獸”
In that case, it's our first one since the one in Fukuoka five years ago.
那就是自福岡以來 有五年不見的大怪獸了
Luckily, there haven't been any victims of Kaiju No. 8 in the past few months.
幸好這幾個月都沒有8號的犧牲者
He doesn't seem the type to attack humans for no reason.
看來並不是見到人就攻擊的類型…
That's right. This strange feeling.
對了，這很不對勁
Why did No. 8 break my weapon without targeting me?
為何8號不是攻擊我 而是打碎武器呢？
His fighting style was very strange.
戰鬥時就一直覺得奇怪
His movements, his reactions.
不管是動作或反應
It didn't feel like I was fighting a kaiju. He was more like a human.
比起怪獸，更像是在和人戰鬥
You should rest for now.
你去休息一下吧
I'll take over from here.
剩下的交給我
No matter what type he is,
無論是什麼類型
if he's a kaiju, he must be neutralized.
是怪獸就格殺勿論
She's exactly right.
說得沒錯
Roger!
瞭解
Captain! Vice-Captain!
隊長！副隊長！
You're too loud, Ikaruga. What's wrong?
太大聲了吧，斑鳩，怎麼了？
I'm sorry, sir. We have some interesting information.
不好意思，因為有令人在意的情報
The kaiju that attacked Furuhashi and Ichikawa
攻擊古橋和市川的人型怪獸
is the same humanoid that appeared during examinations.
應該和測驗會場出現的是同一隻
But when they discovered that kaiju…
但發現怪獸時
they're saying he was in a human form.
他有著人類的樣貌
Hey!
喂！
Hey, did you hear me? Move out of the way?
喂，你有聽到嗎？快點走開
What the hell?!
幹什麼？
Hey, say something!
喂，說話啊
Breaking news.
新聞快報
Upon today's incident, the Defense Force has deemed the humanoid kaiju
基於這次事件 防衛隊將出現在測驗會場
that appeared in the examination arena and Sagamihara as a long-term target
與相模原的人型怪獸 列為長期討伐對象
and has assigned the codename as Kaiju No. 9.
指定代號為怪獸9號
So, how should I kill this
好了，要怎麼殺你好呢？
Kaiju No. 8?
怪獸8號
Oh, this isn't good.
哎呀，不行
I have to incubate until this form fits better.
在習慣前，得好好躲著才行
He's awake.
他醒了
You awake, partner?
喲，醒了啊，搭檔？
Senpai… I'm glad you're safe.
前輩…還好你沒事
That's my line, idiot!
那是我的台詞吧，笨蛋
Also, thank you.
還有，謝謝你
Thank you for saving Iharu-kun and me.
謝謝你救了我和伊春
Why are you thanking Old Man?
你幹嘛向大叔道謝啊？
What? You were here too, Iharu-kun?
嗚喔！伊春，你也在啊？
Kaiju No. 8 was the one that saved us.
救了我們的不是怪獸8號嗎？
It's not that.
不，你看嘛
He noticed the reproductive organs on the yoju. That's huge!
他不是找到了 餘獸的增殖器官，立了大功嗎？
I guess so.
的確是呢
-Thanks, Old Man. -Yeah, no problem.
-謝啦，大叔 -不客氣
But why did that kaiju save us, anyways?
但是那隻怪獸為什麼要救我們呢？
He was super strong.
他超級強的
He took out No. 9's head so easily.
輕輕鬆鬆就把9號的頭打飛了
He's a kaiju, but he was super cool.
明明是怪獸，卻超帥的
I wish you guys could've seen it.
真想讓你們也見識看看
Why are you blushing, Old Man?
大叔你幹嘛害羞啊？
Blushing?
害羞？
He always has this stupid face on!
這傢伙原本就長得這麼蠢啦
-That's true. -I'm glad we're dealing with Iharu-kun.
-好像也是 -幸好要應付的是伊春
No need to punch me that hard.
不用打得這麼用力吧…
FURUHASHI, ICHIKAWA CONGRATS ON YOUR RECOVERY!
（古橋、市川，恭喜出院）
Congrats on your recovery!
恭喜出院！
What is this?
這是？
It's the party to celebrate our first mission.
初次任務的慰勞餐會
We were waiting until you guys were discharged.
我們等到你們出院才辦的
Let's start!
那麼，就開始吧
Here's your full course of A6-ranked kuroge wagyu beef with marbled fat!
為您送上A6級黑毛和牛霜降全餐
A6? I didn't know that existed!
A6？有那種東西嗎？
*IT DOES NOT
（並沒有）
We cannot offer anything less at a party
陽一少爺擔任總召的餐會
with Haruichi-sama as the host!
我們豈能端出丟臉的餐點！
I asked for the most affordable course.
我是拜託老闆準備最划算的套餐
They're only asking for the standard price.
價格就照普通套餐計算
Really? Score!
真的嗎？真幸運
Why does Haruichi have all this power?
陽一是何方神聖啊？
You asked him to host without knowing who he is?
什麼啊？你不知道他是誰 就拜託他當總召嗎？
He's the heir to a major anti-kaiju weapons manufacturer.
他是國內最大的對怪獸兵器製造商
The biggest in the country, Izumo Technology.
出雲科技的少爺
The company that makes the Defense Force suits?
製造防衛隊戰鬥服的那間公司？
Yeah. They're richer than our family could ever imagine.
沒錯，相較之下 我家的財力根本不算什麼
That's why you asked me to find a good restaurant?
所以你才拜託我找店家吧？
Exactly.
沒錯
Because you said you wanted everyone to eat really good food.
如果說想讓大家吃到美味的食物
-The best man for the job, right? -Yeah!
-他不就是最佳人選嗎？ -的確
All right, everyone. Great job on your first mission.
總之，初次任務辛苦了
Being off-duty with your fellow officers all together is a rare opportunity.
同期隊員同時休假的機會不多
Enjoy your time. Cheers!
盡情享受吧，乾杯！
-Cheers!
-乾杯！
So good!
好好吃
His head just flew off! It was so cool!
砰一聲頭就飛走了，超帥的！
I've never seen everyone have this much fun.
我第一次看到大家這麼開心
Thank you for setting this up, Vice-Captain.
謝謝您安排這樣的聚會
You're too soft, Ichikawa. The real party's just beginning.
你太天真了，市川，好戲才正要開始
Huh? What do you mean?
咦？什麼意思？
What the hell?!
你說什麼？
You focus too much on the grandstand plays!
你太愛出風頭了
You let your emotions get out too much!
個人慾望都寫在臉上了！
What? You're one to talk!
啥？你才沒資格說我吧？
If you're super technically skilled like me, you can do those kinds of things.
我這樣高超技術的人另當別論
Hey, guys, don't fight.
等等，不要吵…
You improvise too much. You don't respect the basics.
你這人太我行我素了 有太小看基礎動作的傾向
You stick too faithfully to the basics. You're one step behind everyone.
你才是太忠於基礎動作了 每次聯手攻擊都半慢拍
I'm adjusting my tempo for you.
害我都得配合你
Here, too?
這邊也在吵？
Enough about that. Hey, Izumo-san!
那種事隨便啦，出雲啊
Aren't your suits a little too weak?
你家的戰鬥服也太弱了吧？
I couldn't defeat a single one today!
我連一隻怪獸都打不倒耶
It's your lack of power.
等你能解放更多力量再說吧
Oh no, Senpai's joined in!
連前輩也是
Hey, Communications Team! The network kept getting cut off during strategizing!
話說通訊班 作戰期間的通訊老是斷斷續續的
It's because you kept running into obstacles without permission!
還不是因為你擅自跑到障礙物裡
I told you to tell us when that happened.
明明說過這種情況要先告知
-That way, we can support you! -What?
-這樣我們才能提供支援 -你說什麼？
Oh no, it's happening everywhere!
不好，所有人都吵起來了
But this is…
但這樣子…
So, you've realized, huh?
你發現了嗎？
Before we know it,
不知不覺
everyone's talking about the mission.
大家都在聊任務的話題
They're all seeing what they're lacking after the first mission.
經過第一次任務後 大家都發現自己不足的地方
That's right.
沒錯
It's not just me.
不是只有我而已
Everyone here wants to get stronger!
大家都想要變得更強
What did you say?
你這小子說什麼？
You should respect your elders, you know!
都不知道要尊敬長輩嗎？
I only respect those stronger than me.
我只尊敬比我強的人
Bring it on! Fight me!
好啊，來比賽吧！
I'll show you who's boss!
我要讓你說不出話來！
-Don't get carried away, bastard! -The hell?
-渾蛋，閉嘴聽話，別太囂張了！ -什麼？
That's my line, idiot!
那是我的台詞吧！
You're one stubborn bitch, aren't you?
真的是頑固欸你！
I should be saying that to you!
輪不到你來說！
This happens every summer.
這是每年的慣例呢
I was so happy that you reached out to me, Young Master.
我很高興能收到少爺的邀請
I thought I'd never see you again.
我還以為再也見不到您了
Stop it, Doujima-san.
別這麼說，堂島先生
I just wanted the team to enjoy a good meal.
我只是想讓大家吃到美味的食物而已
And, well, you and your father?
那個，您和您的父親…
I haven't talked to him after that.
在那之後就沒說過話了
-I see. -Sorry for making you worry.
-這樣啊… -抱歉讓你擔心了
Doujima-san, your cooking was phenomenal as usual.
堂島先生 今天的料理一如既往棒極了
Did he hear us?
他聽到了嗎？
I'm taking a piss.
我要去廁所
I guess he's not the type to butt in.
看來他是不會多嘴的類型
All right, quiet down!
好了，全都安靜
It's time to move onto the announcements.
差不多該來發表消息了
The announcements?
消息？
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
Your discovery contributed greatly to our strategy and limiting the damages.
你在作戰中的貢獻 大幅減少了損害，獲得了高度評價
You've been promoted to General Officer.
因此將你升為正式隊員
Welcome to the Defense Force, Third Division!
歡迎加入防衛隊第3部隊
Hell yeah!
-太好啦！
-Senpai! -You did it, Old Man!
-前輩！ -幹得好，大叔
Don't call me old!
別叫我大叔！
-Let's toss him in the air! -Good idea!
-好，把他抬起來慶祝吧！ -好耶
It's a good night, huh?
真是不錯的夜晚
I really hope we don't lose any one of us here.
希望我們不會損失任何人
Wasshoi, wasshoi!
-嘿咻…
Yeah. I hope so, too.
嗯，是啊
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
Starting today, at this hour,
今日此時起
you will no longer be a cadet.
將你從候補隊員
You're officially appointed as a Defense Force Officer.
升格為正式的防衛隊員
I swear to fight with all of my body and soul.
我在此立誓，將全心全意投入戰鬥
Excuse me, ma'am!
那我先告辭了
Don't get carried away.
別高興得太早
You've still got a ways to go before fighting by my side.
要跟我並肩作戰 你還有很長的路要走
So, Mina remembers the promise, too!
米娜果然還記得
Yeah. Just watch me, Mina!
你等著看吧，米娜
You addressed a superior by first name. Fifty push-ups.
禁止直呼長官姓名 罰你伏地挺身五十下再離開
I did it again!
我又說溜嘴了！
Kaiju No. 8 and Kaiju No.9 business
怪獸8號…還有怪獸9號的關係
have summoned me to headquarters.
我必須去本部一趟
That scared me.
嚇死我了
I left everything else to Vice-Captain Hoshina.
後續就由保科副隊長負責
-Ask him about the rest of the paperwork. -Roger!
-那些複雜的手續就去問他吧 -瞭解
Also…
另外
Hoshina was the one that recommended you.
推薦你成為正式隊員的也是保科
Because of your accomplishments in the previous fight, of course.
當然也是因為你在上次戰鬥中的表現
Vice-Captain did?
是副隊長？
Don't let him down.
好好回應他的期待吧
Roger!
瞭解
STUDY ROOM
（自修室）
I should finish up here for today.
今天就先唸到這裡吧
Vice-Captain would yell at me again.
不然又要被副隊長警告了
The training room?
訓練室？
At this hour?
這個時間？
Who's the one that forgot to turn off the lights?
是誰忘了關燈啊？
Vice-Captain? What's he doing?
副隊長？他在做什麼？
Image training?
意象訓練？
These movements…
這些動作…
It's not just any image training.
這不是普通的意象訓練
He's recreating the fight he had with me!
他在重現和我的戰鬥
Oh, it's you, Kafka.
怎麼？是卡夫卡啊？
You were studying this late again?
你又讀書到這麼晚啦？
You too, Vice-Captain. What were you doing this late?
副隊長才是，這麼晚了在做什麼啊？
Oh… Just strategizing for No. 8.
喔，我在思考8號的對策
Next time, I'll slay him in little bits in one slice.
下次遇到時，才能一刀砍了他
I messed up from the first encounter.
說到底，一開始我就搞砸了
If I gave my 100% from the start, I could've beheaded him.
如果一開始就使出全力 應該能把頭砍下來
Also,
還有
if I used Technique Number Six and not Five, I could've shattered his core, too.
要是不用5式而是6式 就能把他連核心大卸八塊
Why are you so scared?
你也太害怕了吧？
A regular officer couldn't fight him.
那不是普通隊員能應付的對手
No. 9 is probably at the same level, too.
恐怕9號的力量也差不多
That's why
他們必須…
I have to kill him.
由我來解決
I knew it. He's so cool.
啊…這個人果然很厲害
He's not just protecting the citizens,
不只有市民
he's trying to protect us, too.
他連隊員也想一起保護
Vice-Captain.
副隊長
I'm going to work hard so I can contribute, sir.
我會努力成為戰力的
Don't get carried away, idiot!
少得意忘形了，白癡！
I don't expect anything from a one-percenter like you!
我根本不覺得 解放戰力1%的傢伙派得上用場
Excuse me, sir.
我先告辭了
But you know…
不過呢
I'll keep my expectations at 1%.
我姑且對你有1%的期待
-I'm going back to the office. Go to bed. -Roger!
-我要回辦公室了，去睡吧 -瞭解
Beginning descent.
開始降落
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻譯：唐詠傑